Pablo Gómez-Caldito

Madrid, Spain | Email: pablo@caldito.me | Website: caldito.me | GitHub: caldito | LinkedIn: caldito

ABOUT ME

I am a very self-taught, curious and proactive person. I love building tools, products and infrastructure using software. My work experience is mainly in SRE, increasing the reliability of online services and implementing the DevOps philosophy in organizations. I also release Open-Source Software projects and have fun learning about Information Security.

SKILLS

Programming Languages: Java, Python, Go, Bash and Javascript.

Technologies: Linux, Ansible, Jenkins, Prometheus, InfluxDB, Grafana, Consul, AWS, GCP, Docker, Containers, Kubernetes, Git, Postgres and MySQL.

Industry Knowledge: Systems design, caching, CI/CD, IaC, SRE, DevOps philosophy, OSS, SDLC, agile methodologies, googling and Al-assisted programming, code review, reading others' code, pentesting (see <u>write-ups</u>), data protection, privacy and anonymity.

Soft Skills: Planning, adaptability, deep work, leadership, knowledge sharing, communication, writing and proactivity.

Languages: English (C1 certified with IELTS) and Spanish (Native).

WORK EXPERIENCE

StreamSets - DevOps Engineer - Madrid, Spain (Remote)

Sep 2021 - Present

Member of a globally distributed team which focuses on the reliability of the system and fastening releases. Mainly working with Jenkins, Terraform, Bash, Ansible, Packer, Maven, AWS, GCP and K8s to manage Java and Scala services and products.

- Increasing significantly every engineer's productivity by re-architecting the build system: Consolidating jobs into multipurpose-multibranch pipelines focused on DevEx and migrating them to a Jenkins managed as code in k8s.
- Ensured the reliability of the system and expanded the understanding of it by performing resilience testing
 against certain infrastructure outages and practicing disaster recovery scenarios.
- Enabled development teams to be autonomous during the SDLC and eliminated 50% of my team's workload with self-serviced Jenkins jobs and lots of documentation.
- Continuously improving team performance by implementing/improving processes: retrospectives, better code review, async communication, well written tasks and championing documentation.

Idealista - Platform Engineer - Madrid, Spain (Remote)

Feb 2020 - Sep 2021

Member of the Platform Team at the leading real estate portal of Southern Europe. Mainly working with: Ansible, Docker for testing, Jenkins, Consul, Prometheus, Grafana, and operating Java and PHP services deployed on a large on-premises network.

- Improved the observability of the infrastructure by designing, implementing and deploying a system that generates Grafana dashboards automatically using Python, Consul and Jsonnet.
- Accelerated 10x the creation of new infra and enabled other teams to take part in the whole SDLC by creating Cookiecutter templates for Ansible Roles and Playbooks. (<u>github.com/idealista/cookiecutter-ansible-role</u>)
- Contributed to many OSS projects. E.g., prevented bugs in idealista's major open-source software project
 prom2teams by creating e2e tests with docker and MockServer (github.com/idealista/prom2teams/pull/214).
- Increased multiple acquired start-ups uptime by refactoring their IaC, creating or upgrading their whole monitoring and alerting stack, and adding CI/CD.

booklil.com - Co-Founder and Software Engineer - Madrid, Spain

Jan 2021 - Aug 2021

Built booklil.com, a second hand book marketplace MVP along with another 3 software engineers. The technologies used were Java (JavaEE and Spring) and Node.js microservices operated on Kubernetes and AWS.

EDUCATION

Universidad Carlos III de Madrid - BSc Computer Science and Engineering - 7.48 / 10

Sep 2017 - Sep 2021

10/10 on Bachelor Thesis: "GitOps continuous deployment and management tool for k8s-based distributed systems".

Relevant Coursework: Programming, Data Structures and Algorithms, Discrete mathematics, Cryptography, Security Engineering, Operating Systems Design, Computer Networking, Distributed Systems and Mobile Device Security.

MOOCs: Docker and Kubernetes: The Complete Guide (Udemy) and Learning How to Learn (McMaster Uni. & UCSD).

FEATURED SIDE PROJECTS

- soup: GitOps operator for Kubernetes built with Go. (github.com/caldito/soup)
- mimcas: Multithreaded in-memory cache server built with Go. (github.com/caldito/mimcas)
- writeups: Walkthroughs of 'boot to root' CTF challenges. (aithub.com/caldito/writeups)

OTHER ACTIVITIES

Tech related: Hackathons, meetups and playing with my homelab.

Other interests: Business, psychology, neuroscience, volunteering, piano, reading and sports.